<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-21T16:16:41+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">James Clancy</title><subtitle>Largely a mess of content. The idea is to generate content then refine sometime in the future.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Redshirts by John-Scalzi</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/09/16/Redshirts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redshirts by John-Scalzi" /><published>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/09/16/Redshirts</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/09/16/Redshirts/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;mildly-amusing-but-not-that-amusing---710&quot;&gt;Mildly amusing but not that amusing - 7/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redshirts tells the story of science fiction characters who have discovered their high fatality rate is do to them being characters on a Sci-Fi TV show. These character then embark on a journey to increase there life spans and engage of various antics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the book was okay and brought up a variety of interesting philosophical topics but was not a page turner and only moderately entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="sci-fi" /><summary type="html">Mildly amusing but not that amusing - 7/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thomas Jefferson and the Tripoli Pirates by Brian Kilmeade</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/09/02/ThomasJeffersonTripoliPirates/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thomas Jefferson and the Tripoli Pirates by Brian Kilmeade" /><published>2022-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/09/02/ThomasJeffersonTripoliPirates</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/09/02/ThomasJeffersonTripoliPirates/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;easy-read-about-little-discussed-historical-events-7510&quot;&gt;Easy read about little discussed historical events 7.5/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in America’s history the nation had no navy and no way to protect US flagged merchants. &lt;em&gt;Thomas Jefferson and the Tripoli Pirates&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of how America’s policy for dealing with pirates shifted from capitulation and ransoms to war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought the book did a great job of explaining the dire and weak position America found itself in immediately after independency. The story is an easy read and provides a good frame of reference to look at the US’s journey from a fledgling country to a superpower.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="history" /><category term="us" /><category term="northern-africa" /><summary type="html">Easy read about little discussed historical events 7.5/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Destiny Disrupted - A History of the World Through Islamic Eyes by Tamim Ansary</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/08/24/DestinyDisrupted/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Destiny Disrupted - A History of the World Through Islamic Eyes by Tamim Ansary" /><published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/08/24/DestinyDisrupted</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/08/24/DestinyDisrupted/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;interesting-details-but-limited-in-scope-710&quot;&gt;Interesting details but limited in scope 7/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destiny Disrupted&lt;/em&gt; tells the history of the world since the founding of Islam through an Islamic perspective. The title generally focused on the middle east, north africa and south asia and told histories that while known are not front and center in western education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, parts of the book were interesting but I feel that book failed to paint a different picture of teh world. It merely drove &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; deeper in history relevant to the Islamic world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="history" /><category term="islam" /><category term="middle-east" /><summary type="html">Interesting details but limited in scope 7/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Confederacy of Dunces by John Kennedy Toole</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/08/17/AConfederacyOfDunces-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Confederacy of Dunces by John Kennedy Toole" /><published>2022-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/08/17/AConfederacyOfDunces%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/08/17/AConfederacyOfDunces-copy/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;pretentious-and-not-all-that-funny-610&quot;&gt;Pretentious and not all that funny 6/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Confederacy of Dunces&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of an over educated and unemployable man who has to venture out from his mother’s house to get a job after his alcoholic mother gets into a car crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the book reminded me of a 1960’s version of the 2012 film, (The Comedy)[https://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/the_comedy]. The main character was generally just unlikeable and unpleasant and not interesting. If the character had been more over the top of antagonistic he might have been likable but overall he just came off as immature.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="new-orleans" /><summary type="html">Pretentious and not all that funny 6/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Exploration of Africa - From Cairo to the Cape</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/08/10/TheExporationOfAfrica/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Exploration of Africa - From Cairo to the Cape" /><published>2022-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/08/10/TheExporationOfAfrica</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/08/10/TheExporationOfAfrica/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;very-generic-you-should-just-read-the-wikipedia-article---510&quot;&gt;Very generic, you should just read the Wikipedia article - 5/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Exploration of Africa&lt;/em&gt; is history book I picked up at the Book Thing. I am assuming it is meant for school libraries or something along those lines. It wasn’t particularly bad but not very interesting. If you need a physical book you can cite for a high school history report this may be for you but otherwise I would just read the Wikipedia page on the exploration of Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">Very generic, you should just read the Wikipedia article - 5/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Naked Economics - Undressing teh Dismal Science by Charles Wheelan</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/08/07/NakedEconomics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Naked Economics - Undressing teh Dismal Science by Charles Wheelan" /><published>2022-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/08/07/NakedEconomics</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/08/07/NakedEconomics/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;mildly-interesting-but-not-particularly-notable---710&quot;&gt;Mildly interesting but not particularly notable - 7/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naked Economics&lt;/em&gt; describes the economy in a whimsical and supposedly approachable way. The book was a relatively easy read and very approachable. Unfortunately the book didn’t dive deep enough in to any particular subjects to really generate real interest. Like liked that the book didn’t shy away from controversial topics like human capital, government market interference and globalism, but all topics in the book were only covered on a surface level.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="economics" /><summary type="html">Mildly interesting but not particularly notable - 7/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Peopleware - Productive Projects and Teams - by Tom DeMarco and Timothy Lister</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/08/04/Peopleware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Peopleware - Productive Projects and Teams - by Tom DeMarco and Timothy Lister" /><published>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/08/04/Peopleware</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/08/04/Peopleware/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-historical-book-about-the-formation-of-teams---910&quot;&gt;Great Historical Book About the Formation of Teams - 9/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peopleware&lt;/em&gt; is a management classic that goes through the construction of teams. The book basically outlines the core values of scrum and agile teams in a pre-agile context. It discusses a number of ways to encourage ownership and collaboration. The most notable example was encouraging a team to shop and cook a spaghetti dinner together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="business" /><summary type="html">Great Historical Book About the Formation of Teams - 9/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homicide- A Year on the Killing Streets by David Simon</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/07/30/Homicide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homicide- A Year on the Killing Streets by David Simon" /><published>2022-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/07/30/Homicide</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/07/30/Homicide/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-decent-book-but-not-the-same-level-as-the-corner-7510&quot;&gt;A decent book but not the same level as The Corner 7.5/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Homicide&lt;/em&gt; tells the stories of homicide detectives that David Simon followed during 1988. The book follows the more traumatic cases several detectives encountered and their following investigations. The book served as the inspiration for the TV show &lt;em&gt;Homicide&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Law and Order&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stories in the book are interesting and well told but the characters were not as developed or relatable as the character’s in &lt;em&gt;The Corner&lt;/em&gt;. Through out &lt;em&gt;Homicide&lt;/em&gt; things are happening around the characters, they are not teh ones driving their own destiny and their choices and decisions are mostly glossed over. While it is a good book and worth reading it is not on the same level as &lt;em&gt;The Corner&lt;/em&gt; and like comparing &lt;em&gt;law and Order&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="baltimore" /><summary type="html">A decent book but not the same level as The Corner 7.5/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">King Solomon’s Mines by H. Rider Haggard</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/07/17/KingSolomonsMine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="King Solomon’s Mines by H. Rider Haggard" /><published>2022-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/07/17/KingSolomonsMine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/07/17/KingSolomonsMine/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;clearly-culturally-significant-but-kind-of-boring-65s10&quot;&gt;Clearly culturally significant but kind of boring 6.5s/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;King Solomon’s Mines&lt;/em&gt; tells the story of several big game hunters who travel north from Durban (ZA) to attempt to locate a legendary diamond mine from a centuries old Portuguese map and look for the protagonists brother. At the novels writing at the end of the 1800’s the areas north of the Natal in South Africa remained largely unexplored by European explorers and a mystery to Victorian society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;King Solomon’s Mines&lt;/em&gt; served as the basis and inspiration for the genre of &lt;em&gt;Lost World&lt;/em&gt; novels and stories. The impact this book had on great novels like the &lt;em&gt;The Heart of Darkness&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Tarzan&lt;/em&gt;. The book was clearly dated but moved at a decent pace and was of an appropriate length. I didn’t find the book particularly riveting but was a worthwhile read as someone who is a fan of the &lt;em&gt;Lost World&lt;/em&gt; genre.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="history" /><category term="fiction" /><category term="lost-world" /><summary type="html">Clearly culturally significant but kind of boring 6.5s/10</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The British Are Coming - The War for America, Lexington to Princeton, 1775-1777 by Rick Atkinson</title><link href="/bookreviews/2022/07/13/TheBritishAreComing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The British Are Coming - The War for America, Lexington to Princeton, 1775-1777 by Rick Atkinson" /><published>2022-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/bookreviews/2022/07/13/TheBritishAreComing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/bookreviews/2022/07/13/TheBritishAreComing/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;informative-and-sometimes-engaging-6510&quot;&gt;Informative and sometimes engaging 6.5/10&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The British Are Coming&lt;/em&gt; is a detailed recount of the early parts of the American Revolution. It begins at the lead up to the conflict and coves till just after the crossing of the Delaware. The book did cover a variety of the conflicts in detail and gave a good amount of  background information on the several interesting military characters such as Admiral Howe. I did find the book well written and sporadically interesting. Unfortunately I feel like the book went a little too far into the weeds for me and lost my interest. If you are extremely interested in the revolutionary war this may be the book for you but I would not consider it a “pop-history” book for general consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>James Clancy</name></author><category term="BookReviews" /><category term="books" /><category term="history" /><category term="usa" /><summary type="html">Informative and sometimes engaging 6.5/10</summary></entry></feed>